Shimamura.
Shimamura.
"-1 day before-"
Un día antes
I somehow ended up back here again.
Por alguna razón, he acabado aquí de nuevo.
Why did we have to become second-years?
¿Por qué hemos tenido que pasar a segundo?
Down below, Shimamura and our new classmates are having PE class.
Abajo, Shimamura y el resto de la clase nueva están haciendo Educación Física.
Does Shimamura even realize I'm up here?
¿Se preguntará siquiera si estoy aquí?
Before I realized it, Shimamura was surrounded by new people,
Cuando me di cuenta, estaba rodeada de gente nueva
and things were going well for her, but not for me.
y las cosas le iban bien, al contrario que a mí.
To put it simply, that's all there is to it.
En resumen, eso es todo.
Shimamura was smiling... with people she barely knew.
Shimamura estaba sonriendo con gente a la que apenas conoce.
And I couldn't find a difference in that smile with the one she showed me.
Y yo no encontraba la diferencia entre esa sonrisa y la que tenía conmigo.
It frustrated me, I couldn't breathe, and I felt like crying.
Me frustraba, no podía respirar y tenía ganas de llorar.
Could it be that there was never anything actually dramatic or special
¿Podría decirse que nunca hubo nada especial
between Shimamura and I?
entre Shimamura y yo?
Shimamura...
Shimamura…
Is she a third-year?
¿Será de tercero?
As she sat a little further down, she started to read her book quietly.
Se sentó lejos de mí y empezó a leer un libro tranquilamente.
This calm takes over the area
Esta calma se apodera de esta área
and I lose my place even here.
y hasta yo pierdo mi sitio aquí.
Oh, hey.
Ah, oye.
Sorry for taking your spot.
Siento haberte ocupado tu espacio.
It's fine.
No pasa nada.
I actually knew that Shimamura would never show up there.
Sabía que Shimamura no se iba a asomar.
Shimamura and I aren't alike.
No somos iguales.
The reason we even met in the gym was because I'm alone
La razón por la que nos conocimos en el gimnasio era porque estaba sola
and Shimamura was bored and left class.
y Shimamura se aburrió y se fue de clase.
That's all there is to it.
No hay más.
Before I realized it, I ended up here.
Cuando me di cuenta, acabé aquí.
What I ended up remembering were precious times with Shimamura.
Terminé recordando los buenos momentos con Shimamura.
It's so boring. Everything's so boring.
Qué aburrimiento. Todo es un aburrimiento.
It's so boring without Shimamura around.
Todo es un coñazo sin Shimamura.
Maybe Shimamura would like something like that.
Puede que a Shimamura le guste.
I'm an idiot.
Soy una idiota.
Why am I looking for something Shimamura might like even now?
¿Qué hago buscando algo que le guste a Shimamura?
S-Sorry.
Lo siento.
Sorry.
Perdona.
Oh, hey. I think you dropped this.
Oye, creo que se te ha caído esto.
That's... Yeah, I did!
Ah, sí.
Thank you. Thank you so much!
Gracias, muchísimas gracias.
I wonder if it was that important.
¿Tan importante era?
You know...
Pero…
I'd never been interested in stuff like that,
aunque no me interesan esas cosas,
but if I had a matching one with Shimamura...
si tuviera uno a juego con Shimamura…
I'm doing it again.
Otra vez.
Why... Why am I crying?
¿Por qué estoy llorando?
This was basically a mirror.
Era un espejo.
I can't stay here.
No puedo quedarme aquí.
Right now, I'm the same as that puppy on display.
Ahora mismo soy igual que los perritos del escaparate.
Actually, I pretty much put myself in that case
La verdad es que yo misma me he puesto en ese lugar.
and instead of being able to attract customers, I'm just sitting there.
En lugar de atraer clientes, me quedo sentada sin hacer nada.
Welcome.
Bienvenida.
"Money, marriage, relationships, I'll predict it all!!"
Dinero, matrimonio, relaciones… ¡Yo lo predigo todo!
Have a seat.
Siéntate.
Are you sure?
¿Estás segura?
If you go home with troubles in your heart,
Si te vas a casa con preocupaciones,
you'll never be able to welcome a wonderful tomorrow.
nunca podrás recibir un futuro maravilloso.
Come, now.
Venga.
Um... Are you a fortuneteller?
¿Eres adivina?
Yes, or perhaps, a fortunegiver.
Más bien, yo doy la fortuna.
I'll tell you anything you need to know. Even...
Te diré todo lo que necesites saber, como por ejemplo
...the reason behind those tears.
la razón por la que lloras.
Simply put...
En resumen…
You must be having romance troubles!
¡Tienes problemas en el amor!
That'll be 1,000 yen.
Son mil yenes.
Okay, here's--
Vale, toma…
Thanks kindly.
Gracias.
Now, then. Let me just ask you one thing.
Bueno, quiero preguntarte una cosa.
Does that person have longer hair than you?
¿Esa persona tiene el pelo más largo que tú?
That person?
¿Esa persona?
The one that's very dear to you.
Esa que tanto aprecias.
Shimamura's hair... is so smooth and pretty... and soft...
Su pelo es tan suave y bonito… y sedoso…
I see.
Ya veo.
If you're already lost in thought, I think I got the idea.
Si ya te has quedado embobada pensando, ya me hago una idea.
Basically, what you are lacking... is enthusiasm!
¡Lo que te falta es… entusiasmo!
You were worried about how others view you and ran away.
Estabas preocupada por cómo te ven los demás y has huido.
It's very obvious what you're lacking.
Lo que te falta es obvio.
I'll tell you a very simple way you can gain enthusiasm.
Te diré una forma sencilla de recuperar el entusiasmo.
Face that direction and scream. Right here, right now.
Mira hacia allí y grita ahora mismo.
If you don't, you'll just waste your 1,000 yen.
Como no lo hagas, habrás tirado mil yenes a la basura.
But if this is what you truly wish for...
Pero si eso es lo que deseas…
I mean, do I really have to do it right here and now?
Pero ¿tengo que hacerlo aquí y ahora?
Do it, if you don't want to have any regrets.
Si no quieres arrepentirte, hazlo.
Now, scream! Scream everything you're feeling with all your might!
¡Grita! ¡Grita todo lo que sientes con toda tu alma!
Throw your arms up and declare it!
Levanta los brazos y dilo.
That's the only way you're going to be able to embrace and steel your heart.
Es la única forma de fortalecer tu corazón.
I-I'll do it...
Está bien, lo haré…
Your voice is too soft and that wasn't the best line.
Lo has dicho en voz baja, no has dicho lo correcto
And you didn't throw up your arms.
y no has levantado los brazos.
You're thinking, "If I had the guts to do that, I wouldn't have this issue."
Estás pensando: "Si pudiera hacerlo, no tendría problemas".
Actually, this whole issue would be resolved if you had guts.
La verdad es que no los tendrías si tuvieras determinación.
Now, one more time.
Venga, otra vez.
I-I'm gonna do my best...
Voy a darlo todo.
But you're clearly not. Now, one more time.
Pues no lo veo. Venga, otra vez.
Huh? Uh...
¿Eh? A ver…
You don't want to have any regrets, do you?
No quieres arrepentirte, ¿verdad?
Then you mustn't run away.
Entonces, no huyas.
Run away...
Huir…
There's something I can't seem to get over.
Hay una cosa que no supero.
I ended up just denying how I felt and just ran away from the start.
Desde el principio he negado lo que sentía y he huido.
But if I'd just stopped and actually talked to Shimamura,
Si me hubiera detenido y hubiera hablado con Shimamura,
none of this would've happened. A part of me regretted that.
nada de esto habría pasado. Hay una parte de mí que se arrepiente.
I won't run away.
No voy a huir.
I'm not going to run away!
¡No voy a huir!
Ooh, excellent. Now, one more time.
Excelente. Venga, otra vez.
Wow, you actually did it.
Vaya, lo has hecho.
People don't need to know the future.
La gente no necesita conocer su futuro.
They need to strongly desire the future.
Solo necesita desear con fuerza lo que quiere.
Um, thanks, I--
Gracias…
Now, if you'll excuse me. May you have a bright future!
Con permiso. Ojalá tengas un futuro brillante.
You again?
¿Otra vez tú?
Retreat!
¡Retirada!
Once the weekend is over, I'll tell Shimamura...
Cuando se acabe el fin de semana, se lo diré a Shimamura…
Or so I told myself and actually came to school, but still, I ended up here.
Eso me dije cuando vine al insti, pero al final he acabado aquí.
This book...
Este libro…
Sorry for taking your spot.
Siento haber ocupado tu espacio.
"Thunderheads and Rain Eiji Kikkawa"
Cumulonimbos y la lluvia Eiji Kikkawa
"Why did I keep running? Because I was scared.
"Por qué seguía huyendo? Porque estaba asustada.
I spend every day afraid thinking about
Todos los días tenía miedo
what if my tomorrow becomes yesterday to the rest of the world
de que mi futuro se convirtiera en el pasado del resto del mundo
as I waste time hesitating.
y perdía el tiempo dudando.
If I'm going to be left behind because of some great change I don't know about,
Si me van a dejar atrás por cualquier gran cambio que desconozco,
I'd rather run to the front and choose a path where I can make the change myself."
prefiero huir hacia delante y elegir un camino donde yo pueda decidir".
Left behind...
Dejar atrás…
I'm not a second-year.
Yo no estoy en segundo.
Only Shimamura was able to become a second-year.
Solo Shimamura está en segundo.
Shimamura is in class right now.
Ahora mismo estará en clase.
She's eating lunch. She's not coming here.
Estará comiendo y no va a venir.
There's no reason she would. Okay, I've got to do this.
¿Por qué iba a venir? Tengo que hacerlo.
I'm not going to run away!
¡No voy a huir!
Yeah, Yamada.
Sí, Yamada.
Being in a club is sort of a pain.
Estar en un club es un coñazo.
There's no room in the place I want to go.
No hay sitio.
Relationships are so hard.
Pero…
Then I'll just have to make room.
Tendré que hacerme un hueco.
Totally!
Claro.
What about you, Shi--?
¿Y tú, Shi…?
Shimamura.
Shimamura.
And that was my official start as a second-year in high school.
Ese fue mi comienzo oficial en segundo.
I wonder how long it'd been since I heard Adachi's voice.
¿Cuánto tiempo hacía que no oía la voz de Adachi?
I think this was the first time in this classroom.
Creo que esa fue la primera vez que la oí dentro de clase.
Can I sit next to you?
¿Puedo sentarme a tu lado?
Huh? Uh, let me get you a seat...
¿Eh? Claro, voy a hacerte un hueco.
Right here is fine.
Aquí me va bien.
I see...
Ya veo…
Oh, Shimamura. I bought some breads.
Por cierto, he traído pan.
Huh? This many? Isn't this a bit much?
¿Eh? ¿Tanto? ¿No crees que te has pasado?
You can have whichever one you want, Shimamura.
Coge el que más te apetezca, Shimamura.
Huh? I, um...
¿Eh? Pues…
Okay, I'll take one.
Venga, cogeré este.
I think I'll have the jam bread.
Me quedaré con el pan de mermelada.
Do you want another one?
¿Quieres más?
N-No, I can't eat that many.
No, no puedo comer tanto.
It was a little embarrassing,
Aunque le dio corte,
but I think she made up her mind that I'm the only one she needed.
creo que ha decidido que yo soy la única que necesita.
I wonder about me, though...
Pero ¿qué hay de mí?
There are times if I even really need anyone, and I still don't have an answer.
Hay veces en las que, aunque necesito a alguien, no obtengo respuesta.
What I did know was my flimsy relationship with Sancho and the others
Lo que sí sabía era que mi relación con las demás
would fade away even before we changed seats again.
desaparecería incluso antes de cambiar de pupitres.
Shimamura.
Shimamura.
Um, let's go home together.
Oye, vámonos juntas a casa.
Sure.
Vale.
Were you just teasing me?
¿Me estás tomando el pelo?
Not at all.
Para nada.
That strap...
Ese colgante…
Are these popular right now?
¿Ahora se llevan?
I think they are.
Creo que sí.
Where did you buy it?
¿Dónde lo has comprado?
Did you want one?
¿Quieres uno?
Yeah, I was thinking of getting one, too...
Sí, estaba pensando en pillarme uno…
Then we'd be matching...
Así lo tendríamos a juego.
So if Adachi got one, she'd be matching with me and Tarumi.
Si Adachi compra uno, iría a juego con Taru y conmigo.
I don't really think so...
No creo…
U-Um, can I hold your hand?
Ah, ¿puedo cogerte de la mano?
Here you go.
Venga.
Why does everyone want to hold my hand so badly?
¿Por qué todo el mundo tiene tantas ganas de cogerme la mano?
Do they all think I'm going to wander off somewhere?
¿Creen que me voy a ir a alguna parte?
Come to think of it, Tarumi takes my left hand,
Ahora que lo pienso, Tarumi me coge la izquierda
but Adachi takes my right.
y Adachi la derecha.
Okay, Adachi. I'll see you later.
Vale, Adachi, nos vemos.
You've got your bike, right?
Tienes tu bici, ¿no?
Yeah...
Sí…
We'll see each other tomorrow.
Nos vemos mañana.
Yeah.
Sí.
You're coming to school, right?
Vendrás a clase, ¿verdad?
Yeah...
Sí…
Because I want to see you...
Es que quiero verte…
No, it's nothing.
No, nada.
Say, Adachi.
Oye, Adachi,
I can't actually go home unless you let go of my hand.
si no me sueltas, no voy a poder irme.
Y-You're not going anywhere...
No te vas a ir a ninguna parte…
You're not going anywhere. Nope, nope, nope...
No te vas a ir a ninguna parte, no, no…
Yeah... She reminds me of a sad little puppy.
Sí… Me recordaba a un perrito.
C-Come here a sec.
Ven un momento.
U-Uh, Adachi?
¿Adachi?
Wh-What's wrong?
¿Qué ocurre?
I...
Yo…
I-I think you're the best, Shimamura...
Creo que eres la mejor, Shimamura.
Uh, where did this... uh, hug come from?
¿A qué viene este abrazo?
We hadn't done anything in a while, so...
Hace mucho que no hacemos nada…
Done anything?
¿Nada?
Because you were with those other girls...
Es que pasas mucho tiempo con otras chicas…
What am I going to do with you?
¿Qué voy a hacer contigo?
Does Adachi not only want me to be her big sister,
¿Adachi no solo quiere que sea su hermana,
but also her mother?
sino también su madre?
If Sancho and the others saw us right now, they'd really get the wrong idea.
Si las otras chicas nos vieran, se llevarían una idea equivocada.
Well, I've gotta get home, little Sakura.
Bueno, tengo que irme a casa, pequeña Sakura.
Why are you treating me like a little kid?
¿Por qué me tratas como una niña?
Um, can I call you later?
¿Te puedo llamar luego?
Call me? Sure?
¿Llamarme? Claro.
I'll call you... around seven.
Te llamaré a eso de las siete.
But I eat dinner around seven...
Pero suelo cenar a esa hora…
Uh, hello?
¿Hola?
Ah, if it isn't Shimamura!
¡Vaya, es Shimamura!
Shimamura!
¡Shimamura!
Sis!
¡Hermanita!
Would you like some strawberry shortcake?
¿Quieres pastel de fresa?
Er, I'm good.
No, gracias.
But where did you guys get money for that?
¿De dónde habéis sacado el dinero?
Um, I think Yachi pulled this cake out of her pocket.
Creo que Yachi se lo ha sacado del bolsillo.
Praise me.
Sí, halágame.
I have decided to become Yashiemon.
He decidido convertirme en Yashiemon.
Yashiemon?
¿Yashiemon?
If there's anything you'd like, Shimamura, just--
Cualquier cosa que quieras…
Yeah, sure, let's go home.
Pues venga, a casa.
I'm home. Hey...
Ya he vuelto…
Can we have dinner earlier? I'm starving.
¿Podemos cenar antes? Me muero de hambre.
I'm making dinner right now.
Estoy preparando la comida.
Oh, would you like some sweet crackers?
¿Quieres galletitas de fresa?
Wait, where did you get those?
¿De dónde las has sacado?
Well, I am Yashiemon.
Por algo soy Yashiemon.
Do you want to eat earlier than everyone else then?
¿Quieres comer tú antes que las demás?
Sure. What's for dinner?
Vale. ¿Qué hay de cena?
Yakitori I just bought.
He comprado yakitori.
Why are you chopping it up like that?
¿Por qué lo estás cortando así?
Oh, how exciting.
Qué emoción.
I made it...
Lo he conseguido.
Knowing Adachi, she'll probably call me right at seven.
Conociendo a Adachi, llamará a las siete en punto.
I wonder if she's sitting very rigidly in front of her phone right now.
Seguramente estará sentada mirando el móvil ahora mismo.
"Adachi Incoming Call"
Adachi Llamada entrante
And here we go. Hello?
Allá vamos. ¿Diga?
Shimamura?
¿Shimamura?
Yup, that's me.
Sí, soy yo.
Good evening. Are your legs asleep?
Buenas noches. ¿Tienes las piernas dormidas?
H-How did you know?
¿Cómo lo sabes?
It was just a guess. So, what's up?
Lo suponía. ¿Qué pasa?
What's up?
¿Qué pasa?
I figured you wanted to talk about something.
Supongo que querrías hablar de algo.
No, not really...
No, no especialmente…
I just hadn't called you for a while...
Hace mucho que no te llamaba.
You don't want to make any friends, Adachi?
¿No quieres hacer nuevos amigos?
Huh? No.
¿Eh? No.
I'm not really interested.
No me interesan.
And...
Y…
"And"?
¿"Y"?
And I have you, Shimamura...
Y ya te tengo a ti, Shimamura…
Did Adachi always talk like this?
¿Hablaba siempre así?
Do you talk to anyone else on the phone, Shimamura?
¿Hablas con alguien más por teléfono, Shimamura?
Well, yeah. Sometimes.
Bueno, sí, a veces.
Oh, you do...
Ya veo.
Why do you sound so sad?
¿Por qué suenas tan decaída?
Because I thought I was the only one...
Porque pensaba que yo era la única.
You're the only one that I call, so...
Yo solo te llamo a ti, así que…
...never mind.
Va, déjalo.
Do you want to just end the call?
¿Quieres que cuelgue?
Well, if we're not going to talk, it's sort of a waste of money.
Si no vamos a hablar, va a ser tirar el dinero.
N-Not at all! I mean...
No, es que…
Because then...
Contigo…
Because then...?
¿Conmigo…?
While I'm on the phone with you, I get to have your time all to myself...
Cuando hablo contigo, acaparo todo tu tiempo.
Say, Adachi.
Oye, Adachi,
You're a bit possessive.
eres un poco posesiva.
Huh? I-I think it's normal.
¿Eh? Yo creo que es normal.
Yeah... I don't know about that.
Bueno, yo no estaría tan segura.
This is totally normal.
Es completamente normal.
I think it's normal...
Creo que es normal…
Well I mean,
Bueno,
in the end, it's not a bad feeling knowing that someone cares about you.
al fin y al cabo no está mal saber que alguien se preocupa por ti.
Um, Adachi...?
¿Adachi?
"Shimamura In Call"
Shimamura Llamada en proceso
Are you okay?
¿Estás bien?
Well... Well...
Es que… Es que…
Himamuwa... You...
Himamuwa… Tú…
When I'm with Adachi, my possibilities are fixed.
Cuando estoy con Adachi, solo tengo una opción.
If I had to choose someone to walk alongside with...
Si tuviera que elegir con quién deseo caminar…
The choices get narrowed down.
Las opciones se reducen.
I should choose whatever's best for me.
Tengo que elegir lo mejor para mí.
It appears that Adachi has chosen the path where she doesn't need anyone else...
Parece que Adachi ha elegido el camino en el que no necesita a nadie más.
"Episode 11: 'The Moon and Determination, Determination and Friends'"
Episodio 11: La luna, la determinación y las amigas
But I...
Pero yo…
"Next Time: 'Friends and Love, Love and Cherry Blossoms'"
Próximo episodio: Amigas, amor y cerezos en flor
Adashimapedia: The final episode.
Adashimapedia: El último episodio.
I've realized something insane.
Me he dado cuenta de una locura.
What's that?
¿Qué?
If we never air the next episode, the final episode will never come!
Si no emitimos el próximo episodio, nunca terminará.
Meaning this anime will never end!
¡Este anime no acabaría nunca!
Pretty sure people will just think it got canceled then.
Entonces, la gente creería que lo han cancelado.